Buford Eeds

Austin, Texas, 78660 | 210-325-3989 | <u>bufordeeds8@gmail.com</u> <u>Github | Medium | LinkedIn</u>

Software Engineer

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and React-based programming and a background in the service industry. Possess strong skills in sales and customer service that help service-oriented companies drive their mission home. Critical thinker with a great deal of versatility to assess a variety of situations honed from experience as a U.S. Marine.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Javascript, React, SQLite3, PostgresQL, HTML, CSS, Heroku

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Tommy Want Wingy - Github | Demo

Improved the customers' online ordering process for one of the most popular food trucks in Austin

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Created a dynamic frontend using React and stored food truck item data and user data in a Ruby on Rails API
- Learned how to manage time and set project goals during solo project

Illuminight - Github | Demo

Deceivingly difficult puzzle game where the objective is to light up all the tiles in a 5x5 grid.

- Created a Single Page Application using React to manipulate the DOM
- Provided authentication and authorization using JWT
- Incorporated MaterialUI framework to provide a consistent and appealing user experience

Flatiron Ping Pong - Github | Demo

Web application built to keep score of ping pong matches and track users' overall record and record versus every other user they have played.

- Built using vanilla JavaScript, Rails API, and bootstrap
- Brainstormed and collaborated with partner daily white-boarding sessions
- Gained experience in pair programming as a driver and navigator

EXPERIENCE

Concierge, eBay, Austin, TX

02 / 2018 - 06 / 2019

- Supported eBay's largest sellers and coached them on best practices to generate more sales
- Exceeded company goals for customer service 6 quarters in a row
- Identified platform bugs and created tickets to send to the engineering team

Sales Counselor, LA Fitness, San Antonio, TX

05 / 2017 - 01 / 2018

- Increased monthly sales revenue by 20% with an average of \$9,200 gross revenue per month.
- Produced a high level of pipeline activity--generated an average of 10 leads per day via external marketing and point of sale referrals. Called 40 prospects and scheduled five appointments a day
- Successfully finalized an average of three sales per day

Psychiatric Nurse Assistant, San Antonio State Hospital, San Antonio, TX

02 / 2016 - 06 / 2017

- Evaluated patients and documented conditions and behaviors in electronic records
- Maintained on-going therapeutic relationships with patients to promote healthy living and social skills

Infantryman, United States Marine Corps, Fort Sam Houston, TX

06 / 2012 - 06 / 2016

- Led Marines during various physical training exercises to ensure combat readiness
- Established and utilized various motivational tactics to promote teamwork and accomplish organizational tasks
- Trained to become a Recon Marine where students learn the basic knowledge of reconnaissance doctrine, concepts, and techniques with emphasis on amphibious entry and extraction, beach reconnaissance and reconnaissance patrolling skills.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School. Austin. TX